In this short video, I'm going to give
you some guidance on how to complete
your word processing assessment.
So ideally you will have downloaded
all of the assessment files
required for this unit at the
beginning, from the My Course page.
Now, as you work through each of the
sessions, you will learn about various
tools and features and functions and
you'll watch some videos and you will
carry out some activities within each of
the sessions, those sessions are designed
to help you build your skills to assist
you in completing the actual assessment.
But when you get to the end of session
one, you then need to have a look at
the actual assessment and answer the
questions in the assessment booklet.
So what I'm going to do, I'm just going
to open up the actual assessment booklet.
So these are the files I've downloaded
and I have here the assessment.
So I just double click on that.
Open the assessment.
As you can see, once I've opened the
assessment, you don't need to put your
name on the top or anything like that
because this is electronic and it is your
file and can only be submitted by you.
And what you will see is you'll have
all of the different parts and all of
the learning outcomes that are covered.
Within word processing, presentations
and spreadsheets, you will also
complete elements of the Improving
Productivity Using IT unit.
This is a mandatory unit and it has been
embedded within each of the actual units.
So in the assessment,
you're given a scenario.
And the first thing to do is read
through the scenario carefully
and then make a note of the second
box here, which is about describe,
explain, identify, and list.
Primarily the word processing and
spreadsheets and PowerPoints is
about using tools and features
and functions within the software
to carry out a range of tasks.
However, you are asked to answer
questions, and it is important that when
you are answering the questions that you
understand what the command verb is such
as describe, explain, identify, and list.
And we have detailed on here exactly
what's required when it is a description,
you need to give a description so
it should be a detailed account.
The easiest way to look at it is if
you're asked a question, try to provide as
much detail as possible, which will then
allow your tutor to see that you fully
understand what the question is asking.
You then need to come on to the
first part of the assessment,
which is several questions.
And it will ask you: identify
what types of information.
And then the second one is
about storing your assessment
document in a suitable location.
And you need to provide a screen print of
the location of the assessment document,
not the assessment document itself,
open like this, but the actual folder.
So if your screenshot is saved in a
folder, your document's saved in a folder,
the screenshot should represent that.
So this would be the screenshot
that I would take and place in
the box on the actual assessment.
So, a good idea is to work through
each of the parts of the assessment.
Answer the questions.
If you're not sure you can always refer
back to the various sessions within the
actual course materials to assist you.
And as you work through, you're
asked to complete a range of tasks.
I always recommend to people that
once you've completed a task,
a good idea is to highlight it.
So I'll highlight that in green,
which indicates that actually
have completed that task.
If there's anything I'm not sure of,
I can always come back to that and
I tend to highlight those in yellow.
That just means that I need to
come back to that if I'm not sure,
look at the course materials and
then come back to the assessment.
And again, once completed, I would just go
back in and highlight that again in green.
An important point to note is
that you should complete all seven
or eight parts of an assessment.
If there are seven parts, complete all
of the parts do not work through and
get to part three or part four, and
then stop and submit that to your tutor.
Your tutor will not be able to mark it
unless you fully complete the assessment.
And once you're satisfied that you've
fully completed check through your
work, and then you should submit your
work to your tutor for assessment.
If you are unsure of anything and
you're unable to find the information
or you're unsure of what to do.
The first point of contact
would be your tutor who will be
able to assist you with that.